在这里看日出真美
The sunrise is beautiful from up here.
老实说  我都不记得上次看日出是什么时候了
To be honest, I can't remember the last time I saw the sun rise.
真的
Really?
得有点什么非常特别的事
It takes something pretty special
才能让我早上7点起床
to get me up before 7:00 a.m.
我记得  我昨晚就很特别
As I recall, I was pretty special last night.
你又让我惊喜了
There--you surprised me again.
事实上  这一切让我也有点意外
You know, the truth is I'm a little surprised by all this myself.
什么意思
What do you mean?
意思是  你消失了将近一年
Well, I mean, you disappear for nearly a year,
然后  突然有一天你开着雪佛兰57就来了
and then, one day, you suddenly show up in a '57 Chevy--
是法拉利72年  不过好吧
'72 Ferrari, but, yeah.
你让我倾倒
And you sweep me off my feet.
我喜欢这样
And I liked it.
很好  我原本不确定你会不会喜欢
That's good 'cause I wasn't sure you would.
当然了  你还不真的了解我
Of course you weren't. You don't really know me yet.
到昨天为止  我们共度了大概50个小时
Till yesterday, we'd spent about 50 hours together,
而我们大部分时间都在谈你
and we'd spent most of them talking about you.
是啊  这就是我喜欢我们恋情的地方
I know, and that's what I love about our relationship.
-哈维  -宝拉
- Harvey... - Paula...
你说我觉得你想说的话之前
Before you say what I think you're gonna say,
让我说
let me say
你或许比任何人都了解我
you may know me better than anyone.
现在  我也想了解你
And now I'd like to get to know you too.
那好啊
I'd like that.
我猜我想说的是  我采取了不理智的行为
I guess what I'm trying to say is I acted irrationally,
但是求你  塔拉  只要再给我一次机会
but please, Tara, if you could just give me another chance...
我保证  我再不会让你失望了
I promise you that I will never let you down again.
你知道你不能这么说  路易
You know you can't say that, Louis.
抱歉  什么  这是我的角色扮演
Wait, I'm sorry, what? This is my role play.
我想说什么就能说什么
I can say whatever the hell I want.
我们谈过你对自己的行为提出
And we've talked about you making bold proclamations
大胆宣告的事了
about your own behavior.
那跟这有什么关系
What does that have to do with this?
你刚保证绝不会再让塔拉失望
You just promised to never let Tara down again.
这是不切实际的
That is unrealistic.
当你不可避免地打破这一承诺时会怎样
What happens when you inevitably break that promise?
我会道歉  并保证再不那么做了
I'll apologize and promise I'll never do it again.
你看不出这模式的问题吗
And you don't see a problem with that pattern?
我看到的是  利普希茨医生
What I see, Dr. Lipschitz,
我们的谈话已经进行了46分钟
is we're 46 minutes into this session,
我还没有得到我的了结
and I haven't gotten closure yet.
路易  我们就你母亲
Louis, we spent seven years on the fact
逼你穿埃斯特的旧衣服的事谈了七年
that your mother made you wear Esther's hand-me-ups.
你50分钟内是得不到了结的
You're not getting closure in 50 minutes.
那我付钱给你做什么
Well, then what the hell am I paying you for?
好吧  路易
Okay, Louis.
究竟发生什么事了
What's really going on here?
不是因为塔拉
It's not about Tara.
是孩子
It's--It's about the baby.
我担心我永远做不了父亲
I'm just worried I'll never be a father.
我觉得下周我们正好可以从这里讲起
I think that's a good place for us to pick up next week.
-搞什么  -路易  冷静
- What the fu--? - Louis, calm down.
不  我刚把我最深的恐惧告诉了你
No, I just told you my deepest fear
那就是我的时间不多了
is that my clock is running out,
而你只在乎你的宝贝时间
and all you care about is your precious time?
你有没有想过  你没有时限
Has it ever occurred to you that you don't have a clock
你什么时候都能要孩子
and can have children whenever you want?
你好意思说这种屁话
Well, that sounds like a load of crap coming from a guy
你还在看表呢
who's looking at his clock.
你的偶像托尼・兰道尔呢
What about your idol, Tony Randall?
天呐
Oh, my God.
托尼・兰道尔第一个孩子是他77岁时出生的
Tony Randall fathered his first child at 77.
医生  这太棒了
Doc, this is fantastic.
所以  下周前你没问题了
So you're good till next week.
你疯了吗  我都要崩溃了
What, are you nuts? I'm teetering.
取消明天一下午的预约
Clear up tomorrow, all afternoon.
我当时在单位
I was at work.
孩子的日托所打来
It was the kids' daycare calling.
香农没去
Shannon never showed up.
然后呢
And then what happened?
然后警方来电话了  我的世界终结了
Then the police called. My world ended.
一个月后
And one month later,
我收到了保险公司的来信
I got a letter from the insurance company
说香农在申请时撒谎了
saying Shannon lied on her application.
关于什么
About what?
他们说她吸烟
They're claiming she was a smoker.
-是这样吗  -不  她五年前就戒了
- Was she? - No, she quit five years ago,
而且这事她早说了
and she was totally up-front about it.
那他们为什么认为她申请时撒谎了
So then why would they think she lied on her application?
因为这个
Because of this.
这是香农在她亲戚婚礼上的照片
It's a picture of Shannon at her cousin's wedding.
他们跟索赔拒付信一起寄来的
They sent it to me along with her denied claim.
请告诉我这照片是五年前的了
Please tell me this picture is over five years old.
是八个月前的
It was taken eight months ago.
他们肯定是看了她的脸书主页
They must've gone into her Facebook page.
该死
Shit.
就那么一根烟  我还狠狠地说她了
It was one cigarette, and I gave her hell for it.
那无所谓  不论是一根还是一百根
It doesn't matter if it was one or a hundred,
他们足以凭此称她的保单无效
it's enough for them to claim her policy is null and void.
我妻子死于了车祸  罗斯先生
My wife died in a car accident, Mr. Ross.
她是个健康的39岁女人
She was a healthy 39-year-old woman.
她因为赶着下班接孩子而死
She died rushing from her job to pick up our children.
这跟抽烟有什么关系
What the hell does any of this have to do with smoking?
是不该有任何关系
It shouldn't have anything to do with it,
但是这家公司的使命不是帮助他人
but this company is not in the business of helping people.
而是挣钱
It's in the business of making money.
如果他们能找到理由拒付
So if they can find any reason not to honor a claim,
他们就会抓住机会
they'll take it.
没有保险的赔付  我们会失去房子
Without that insurance money, we're gonna lose our home.
求你  我的孩子已经失去够多了
Please--my children have lost enough.
我会想办法的
I'll find a way.
看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal
给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife
所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel
所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like
豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind
我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money
好了*
*All right
退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance
诉讼双雄
第七季  第二集
美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie
我不知道有人搬进来了
I didn't know anybody was moving in here.
看起来不错
It looks great.
当一切尘埃落定  我们将会请一个新合伙人
Well, as it turns out, we're getting ourselves a new partner,
他们也需要一个新办公室所以
and they needed a new office, so.
新合伙人  太棒了
New partner? That's fantastic.
说明我们已经重新站稳了
Shows we're back on our feet.
他们是那家律所来的
What firm are they from?
-这家  -没听懂
- This one. - I don't understand.
只是因为他们还没宣布罢了
That's 'cause it hasn't been announced yet,
不过你现在正注视着皮尔逊-
but you're looking at the newest senior partner
斯佩克特-利特的新高级合伙人
at Pearson Specter Litt.
恭喜你唐娜  你一定很开心
Congratulations, Donna. You must be thrilled.
我是很开心
I am.
我也知道你现在在想什么
And I know what you're thinking--
一个小秘书怎么能当合伙人呢  但
how can a secretary be made a partner? But--
我不会这么想的唐娜
I wasn't thinking that, Donna.
我知道你工作有多努力
I know how hard you work
也知道你对这间公司和这里的每个人意味深重
and how much you mean to this firm and everyone in it.
谢谢你  卡特里娜
Thanks, Katrina.
不客气  你忙吧
You're welcome. I'll let you get back to work.
我只是说你太操之过急了
All I'm saying is I think you're rushing it.
而且  当你推翻了一个独裁者之后
And I'm saying that, when you overthrow a dictator,
你不应该还把他们的雕像留在广场上
you don't leave their statue up in the square.
你应该连雕像都清除
You tear it the hell down.
你不认为这么说其实是告诉了大家
You don't think that this sends a message
你还需要证明你自己吗
that you have something to prove?
哈维  你还记得阿瑟・里夫斯不
Harvey, do you remember Arthur Reeves?
你说扮演超人的那个演员
You mean the guy who played Superman?
那是乔治・里夫斯
That was George Reeves.
阿瑟・里夫斯创建了这家律所
Arthur Reeves founded this firm.
当高登  斯密特和范・戴克把他驱逐出城时
And when Gordon, Schimdt, and Van Dyke ran him out of town,
他们不单单只是把他墙上的名字拿掉
they didn't just tear his name off the wall.
还打给他最大的客户滚蛋
They called his biggest client
自己找个新律所
and told them to pack up their shit and find another firm.
你想说什么
What's your point?
我想表达他们希望大家都知道
My point is they wanted the world to know
新掌门人来了
there was a new sheriff in town,
这行为传达的不是你需要证明自己
and the message that sends isn't that you have something to prove--
而是你已经掌控一切了
it's that you're in charge.
而且会继续掌控下去
And you're staying that way.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
希望你不要介意我擅自把它挂起来了
Hope you don't mind I took the liberty of hanging that.
我猜猜  是你作为我秘书的最后一个剪影
Let me guess-- it's your last official act as my secretary.
我以前告诉过你我不会丢下你不管的
I told you once before I wouldn't leave you high and dry.
谢谢你  唐娜
Thanks, Donna.
不客气  哈维
You're welcome, Harvey.
说到不再是你秘书这件事
And speaking of not being your secretary anymore...
这是宣布我当合伙人的新闻稿
This is a press release announcing my partnership.
它不单单只是一个新闻稿
It's more than just a press release.
它是给整个世界的宣言
It's a statement to the world.
放着好了我等下会看
I'll take a look at it later.
你是指下午看还是
Do you mean, like, later this afternoon
等你去看阿加德医生之后
or later, like, after you go see Dr. Agard?
-什么  -哈维  上次我不想当你秘书时
- What? - Harvey, the last time I stopped being your secretary,
你就整个慌掉了
you started having panic attacks,
我不是说你这次会重蹈覆辙
and I'm not saying that's gonna happen again,
然而你的表情刚刚暴露了
but you just got a look on your face,
而且我想确保这一切你是支持的
and I wanna make sure you're okay with all of this.
我没意见的  唐娜
I'm okay with it, Donna.
我会打点好你所有需要发布新闻稿的一切
I'll get you what you need to issue that release,
但现在  我要先搞定我自己那份
but, right now, I gotta make a statement of my own.
有什么能够帮到你呢  罗斯先生
What can I do for you, Mr. Ross?
不如从给哈利・克里斯特开支票开始
Well, you can start by writing a check to Harry Kirst.
-你不是来浪费时间的吧  -不是的
- You don't waste time, do you? - No, I don't.
那不如你给我客户30万
So why don't you cut my client a check for $300,000,
然后我撤回尚未上诉的案件
and I'll withdraw this lawsuit I haven't filed yet.
罗斯先生  恐怕你有一些理解失误
Mr. Ross, I'm afraid there's been a little misunderstanding here.
我们没想要庭外和解
We're not looking to settle.
那你约我开什么会
Then why the hell did you set this meeting?
程序所需  我们需要和客户见面
Cause it's policy to meet with our clients
为解决他们的问题作出尝试
and try to resolve their issues.
好  我客户的问题是你们不遵守和他的合同
Okay, well, my client's issue is you're not honoring his claim
导致他无法继续抚养小孩
so he can't support his children.
对此我感到非常抱歉
Yes, and I'm very sorry about that,
然而我无能为力
but my hands are tied.
我懂
I get it.
你们的政策就会推诿责任
Your policy is to give people the runaround
令他们大受打击然后撤诉
so they get demoralized and drop their case.
不  罗斯先生  我们的政策是照章办事
No, Mr. Ross, our policy is to follow the letter of our contracts,
如果我们让一个客户在申请表上撒谎
and, if we let one person who lied on their application
而毫发无损地拿赔偿的话
get away with it,
我们不用做生意了
we wouldn't have a business anymore.
看着我
Look at me.
我不是什么民事人身伤害小律师好吧
I'm not some personal injury lawyer, all right?
我是皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所的
I work at Pearson Specter Litt.
我不会善罢甘休的
I'm not gonna get worn down.
所以我建议你们赔钱了事
So I suggest you just cut me a check.
你们也无需在公堂上被我弄得颜面无光
Save yourself the trouble of me wiping the floor with you in court.
我说过了  我无能为力
As I said, my hands are tied,
但是我不会是和你对簿公堂的那个
but it won't be me you'll be going up against in court.
外聘律师阿克曼先生才是和你打擂台的
It'll be our outside counsel, Mr. Ackerman.
而且就我所知
And, from what I've seen,
没有人不会在阿克曼先生面前败下阵来
nobody wipes the floor with Mr. Ackerman.
你的办公室不错啊
Nice office.
不过我的更好
Mine's better.
你不是用过这句台词了
Isn't that the same line you used
在你觉得你的法拉利比我的眼镜蛇好的时候
when you thought your Ferrari was better than my Cobra?
它确实比较好啊
It was better.
而且好台词总不会过时的
And a good line never gets old.
怎么不和你日渐高耸发际线说
Tell that to your hairline.
怎么不和你日渐松弛的腰际线说
Tell that to your waistline.
好久不见  哈维
Good to see you, Harvey.
什么风把你吹过来了
What brings you down?
想和你结束掉我们几年前开始过的对话
I'm here to finish a conversation we started years ago.
我知道你不会来这里工作
Well, I know you're not coming over here,
那你一定是想说让我到你那边去了
so you must be talking about me working over there.
若我正有此意呢
What if I am?
我会问"你想要我的哪一个客户"
I'd say "Which one of my clients are you after?"
因为我们都清楚你不能把辉瑞制药拿走
because we both know you can't have Pfizer.
不  我可以
Yes, I can.
你的意思是你为了挖我
Are you telling me you're ready to drop
而准备放弃掉杰西卡最早的客户吗
Jessica's oldest client just to get me?
我就是这个意思
That's what I'm telling you.
为什么现在出手
Why now?
因为杰西卡走了  所以如今我能够这么做了
Because Jessica's gone, so now I can.
-那你得让我当冠名合伙人  -什么
- Then make me name partner. - What?
这事不在于杰西卡走了所以你有权力了
This isn't about Jessica's gone so now you can--
而是在于杰西卡走了
this is about Jessica's gone,
所以如今你想告诉全世界你不是她
so now you wanna tell the world that you're not her.
而且你的重点也不是挖我
And that's not about hiring me.
而是想要我的客户
That's about getting my client.
亚历克斯  这是双赢
Alex, this is a win/win.
我不偷偷挖你墙角  你过来  你我都开心
I don't poach. You come over. We have fun.
但我不会就这么轻易让你掌控我的地盘的
But I'm not gonna just give you the run of the place.
那我就不去了
Then I'm not coming.
因为一年之内我的名字就能上这里的墙
Because my name is going up on this wall within a year.
而辉瑞制药也不会离开我
And Pfizer's not leaving me.
-亚历克斯...  -你总说你牌技比我好
- Alex-- - You always say you're the better poker player.
但今天可不是这种情况
Well, not today,
因为我赌注全下了  而你手里根本没牌
because I'm all in, and you got nothing.
所以要么让我当冠名合伙人
So either add my name to your letterhead
不然就带着你的筹码回家吧
or take your chips and go home.
法官大人  随他们如何狡辩
Your Honor, they can dress this up all they want,
但事实就是死者签订合同时主观有恶意
but the fact is the deceased entered into a contract in bad faith
她慌称自己不再吸烟了
by claiming she was no longer a smoker.
场上唯一的事实就是他们捏造了一个理由
The only fact here is that they're manufacturing a reason
来逃避合理的索赔
to weasel out of a legitimate claim.
你是在向庭上声称我们捏造了这张
Are you gonna tell the court that we manufactured
你客户在八个月之前吸烟的照片吗
this picture of your client smoking eight months ago?
我十分清楚你们送给那位悲伤的丈夫的照片
I'm well aware of the photo that you sent a grieving husband,
但一张并没有显示该女子在吸烟的照片
but an image of a woman not inhaling a cigarette
并不能说明什么
doesn't prove anything.
她在申请的时候撒谎了
She lied on her application.
这和她的死因毫无关系
Which had nothing to do with how she died.
但她的死因并非我们的诉讼焦点
And manner of death isn't at issue here.
-合同才是  -他说得有道理
- The contract is. - He's got a point.
法官大人  他们声称我的客户
Your Honor, they're claiming that my client
签订合同时主观上有恶意
entered into a policy in bad faith.
那当一家公司翻遍了一名女子的社交媒体记录
Well, what kind of faith is it when a company
只为了欺负她的丈夫和三个孩子时
pores through a woman's social media history
他们算是想打什么主意
just to stick it to her grieving husband and three children?
总比一个在过去三年里
Better faith than a man that pretended to be an attorney
假冒律师的人强
for the better part of three years.
这话什么意思
What are you talking about?
法官大人  这是罗斯先生的哈佛学位证
Your Honor, this is Mr. Ross' Harvard diploma.
问题是罗斯先生根本就没上过哈佛
The only problem is Mr. Ross never actually went to Harvard.
他倒是在丹伯里联邦监狱待过
The only place he did graduate from was Danbury Federal Prison
服刑原因就是冒充律师
where he spent time for impersonating a lawyer.
够了  这完全是无用且无关的信息
All right, that is inadmissible and irrelevant.
你说我们恶意  你的整个人生都充满恶意
You're claiming bad faith. Your whole life is bad faith.
我觉得陪审团应该了解这一点
I think a jury should have a chance to hear that.
法官大人  这简直...
Your Honor, this--
我拒绝你驳回诉讼的请求  阿克曼先生
Your motion to dismiss is denied, Mr. Ackerman,
但是  罗斯先生  我倾向于认为
but, Mr. Ross, I am inclined to agree
你的过往和本案相关  这就意味着
that your history is relevant to this case, which means,
假如他想把这点拿到庭审上去说
if he wants to bring it up at trial,
我是不会制止他的
I'm not stopping him.
你就是打算玩这招吗
So that's how you're gonna play it?
什么
Excuse me?
你现在不打算告诉我
You're not gonna give me
你们实际能出的和解费吗
your real settlement offer right now?
我完全不明白你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
放屁  我就知道那女的之前没给我报价
Bullshit--I knew there was a reason that woman
是有原因的
didn't give me an offer before.
现在我明白了  是因为你想让我目睹那一幕
Now I know it's because you wanted me to see that.
既然你提到这个  我确实利用职权
Now that you mention it, I did take the liberty
设定了一个小小的和解条件
of whipping up a little standard boilerplate.
不承认过错  你们就能获得一点点和解费
No admission of guilt, you settle for pennies on the dollar,
一口价
and that's take it or leave it.
那我现在就告诉你  我们不接受
Well, then let me tell you right now we're leaving it.
你有义务把我们的报价告知你的客户
You're required to present this to your client.
我也有义务向他们提供法律意见
Well, I'm also required to give them my legal opinion,
告诉他们你们败诉后给的钱会比这多得多
which is that you stand to lose a lot more than that.
也许你没注意到刚刚在里面发生了什么
Maybe you missed what just went on back there.
刚刚在里面法官支持了我的诉讼请求
What went on back there is the judge ruled in my favor,
而你没能成功地驳回诉讼
and you didn't get your case dismissed.
同时他也表态了
He also showed his hand.
当12名陪审团成员发现审理此案的人
Now, how do you think 12 jurors are gonna rule
显然根本都不信任你时
when it's plain as day that the guy hearing the case
你觉得他们会如何判
doesn't even trust you?
-很好  你们都到了  -当然了
- Good, you're here. - Of course we are.
管理合伙人召开会议
When the managing partner calls a meeting,
所有合伙人都得出席
the rest of the partners show up.
你想和我们谈些什么
So what'd you want to talk about?
我想谈谈把辉瑞制药拉来当我们的客户的事
I wanna talk about bringing on Pfizer as a client.
哈维  我相信你清楚这一点
Harvey, I'm sure you already know this--
那样意味着放弃吉姆・雷诺兹
that would mean dropping Jim Reynolds.
我想这就是重点
I think that's the point,
而且我觉得这个主意棒极了  哈维
and I think it's a great idea, Harvey.
辉瑞制药的规模是吉姆・雷诺兹的十倍
Pfizer's ten times the size of Jim Reynolds,
但杰西卡在这件事上一直很固执
and Jessica's always been stubborn about him.
那就好  因为要想达成这个目的
Good, because, in order to do that,
我们得让亚历克斯・威廉姆斯当冠名合伙人
we need to make Alex Williams a name partner.
-什么  -你以为把辉瑞制药拉过来的人是谁
- What? - Who do you think's bringing Pfizer over here in the first place?
那就给他一件有无敌风景的大办公室啊
So then give him a corner office with a killer view
因为我是不会让一个我都不怎么认识的人
because I'm not gonna do something like that
-当冠名合伙人的  -哈维...
- for someone I barely know. - Harvey--
我和他认识了15年了
Well, I've known him for 15 years,
我为他作担保
and I'm vouching for him.
就算你和他是一个娘胎里出来的
I don't care if you came out of the womb with him.
你不能为了拉到一个客户
You don't just slap somebody's name
就随便把某个人的名字拍上墙
on the wall to get a client.
我不仅仅是把他的名字拍上墙  路易
I'm not just slapping his name up, Louis.
我在做正式动议
I'm making a move.
-哈维...  -够了
- Harvey-- - Hey, that's enough.
我昨晚问了你们对我当老大有没有意见
I asked you last night if you had any problems with me calling the shots,
你们说没有
and you said you didn't.
你到底同不同意
Now, are you on board with this or not?
好吧  哈维  我同意
Okay, Harvey, I'm on board.
终于找到你了  我需要你帮忙
Ah, there you are. I need your help.
在我安安静静地吃完我的火腿三明治后
And you can have it after I've enjoyed
我就可以帮你的忙了
my ham sandwich in peace.
不行  不好意思  你得等等再吃了
Nope, sorry, that ham's gonna have to wait.
哈维要让某个陌生人当冠名合伙人了
Harvey is about to make some stranger name partner.
什么  路易  你一定是搞错了
What? Louis, you must've misunderstood something.
格蕾琴  我听得真真切切
Gretchen, I heard him clear as a frickin' bell.
他想要这家伙的一个客户  冠名合伙人
He wants one of the guy's clients, name partnership
则是代价  我认为这是个天大的错误
is the price, and I think it's a huge mistake.
-那你有那么告诉他吗  -当然说了
- Well, did you tell him that? - Yes, of course,
但是他听不进去
but he couldn't hear me.
我昨晚告诉他我会支持他的决定的
And I told him last night that I would back his decisions.
也就是说你想让我去尽可能多的
Which means you want me to find out as much dirt
找到那个人的黑料  这样你就可以说服哈维
as I can on the sucker so you can convince Harvey
不要雇佣他
not to hire him.
正是这样  所以请你赶紧出手
Exactly, so let's move this little piggy to the market
-去...  -那是不可能的  路易
- and go-- - Not gonna happen, Louis.
格蕾琴  你没有听到我刚刚说的吗
Gretchen, did you not hear what I just said?
我听到了  你没听过
I heard you. Have you never heard the saying
"要剥猫皮  不只一法"的说法吗
"There's more than one way to skin a cat"?
你是说"要喂饱猫"吧
You mean "Stuff a cat."
我为什么要说"要喂饱猫"
Why would I mean "Stuff a cat"?
因为他们是美好的生物
Because they are glorious creatures,
只有野蛮人才会剥猫的皮
and only a barbarian would skin one.
路易  你的思考方式不对
Louis, your brain is not right.
我的意思是  如果哈维想要这个人的客户
My point is, if Harvey wants this man's client,
一定还有别的办法可以得到他们
there has to be another way to get them.
天啊  你说得对
Holy shit. You're right.
如果我能拉到辉瑞这个客户  哈维甚至根本
If I can get Pfizer, Harvey doesn't even have to bring
都不用把这个小丑招到公司里了
this clown to the firm at all.
系上安全带  格蕾琴  因为我们要
Strap in, Gretchen, because we're about to get
撸起袖子  把这只猫喂到吐
elbow-deep into stuffing the shit out of this cat.
我走了[没法吃了]
And I'm out.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我是说  我知道这个报价很糟糕
I mean, I get that the offer is horrible,
但是如果法官允许这案子上庭
but if the judge is letting this thing go to trial,
他一定认为我是有案可立的
he must think I have a case.
的确是这样  哈利
You do have a case, Harry.
但是对方律师很明确
But the lawyer on the other side of this thing has made it clear
他会使尽浑身解数
that he is willing to pull out all of the stops,
无论多么低级
no matter how low.
他们已经用了香农的照片
They already used the photo of Shannon.
他们还有什么
What else do they have?
-我  -什么意思
- Me. - What are you talking about?
我现在是个完全获得许可的律师协会的一员
Look, I am a fully-licensed member of the bar now,
但是在这之前  我...
but, before I was, I--
我是无证上岗  并且被逮到了
I was practicing law without a license, and I got caught.
你不觉得应该告诉我吗
And you didn't think I should know that?
我不认为那和案子有关
I didn't think that it would be relevant.
现在看来是肯定有关了
It sure as hell seems relevant.
他们只是想要陪审团对我产生偏见
They are just trying to prejudice the jury against me--
他们想要陪审团对你产生偏见  反正我会
They're going to be prejudiced against you--I'd be.
我还是可以赢下这个案子的
I'm telling you that I can still win this.
还是可以赢  他们要让这案子看起来像是
Still win? They're gonna make it seem like
香农故意撒谎  之后我去
Shannon lied on purpose, and then I went out
雇了个骗子来掩饰
and hired a liar to cover it up.
如果你想把案子交给别人
If you want someone else to handle this,
我完全理解
I... completely understand.
唯一的问题是  在我找你之前
The only problem with that is I went to 15 firms
我去了15家律所
before I came to you,
因为那张照片  没有一家愿意接我的案子
and none of them would take my case because of that photo.
你是我最后的希望了  罗斯先生
You were my last hope, Mr. Ross,
现在你告诉我我们要输了
and now you're telling me we're gonna lose.
不  哈利
No, Harry.
我向你保证  我不会让你输掉这个案子的
I am promising you that I will not cost you this case.
很好  唐娜  你在这
Good, Donna, you're here.
需要有人来起草亚历克斯的合同
I'm gonna need someone to draw up a contract for Alex, and--
哈维  我觉得我们不应该放弃吉姆・雷诺兹
Harvey, I don't think we should drop Jim Reynolds.
-什么  -我理解你在做什么
- What? - I understand what you're doing,
但是我觉得也许你有点太着急了
but I think that maybe you're rushing into it.
我不着急  唐娜  我只是很果断
I'm not rushing, Donna. I'm being decisive.
那么在你这么做之前你得告诉杰西卡
Then you need to tell Jessica before you do it.
告诉杰西卡
Tell Jessica?
我这么做是为了宣布现在这是我的律所了
I'm doing this to show people that this is my firm now.
寻求妈咪的许可并不在计划之中
Asking Mommy's permission isn't part of the plan.
那么向你剩下的长期委托人
Well, is it also part of the plan
发出如果遇到更大的委托人
that you signal to the rest
你就会弃他们不顾的信号
of our long-term clients
也在计划之中吗
that you'll just throw them over for the next big thing?
你到底怎么了
Where the hell is this coming from?
什么叫"你到底怎么了"
What do you mean "Where is this coming from?"
你让我当合伙人  我在说我的看法
You made me a partner. I'm saying my piece.
那是开会的作用
That's what the meeting was for.
也许你没发现  但是你和路易
Well, maybe you didn't notice, but you and Louis were having
-是在单独会谈  -你知道吗  唐娜
- a private meeting. - Well, you know what, Donna?
你有胆量要上桌的资格
You had the balls to ask for a seat at the table.
那下一次你有什么要说的
So the next time you have something to say,
有胆量在会议中说出来
have the balls to say it at the goddamn meeting.
今天在庭上怎么样
How'd it go in court?
不怎么样
Not great.
不会吧  别告诉我法官同意撤销这个案子
No, don't tell me the judge agreed to dismiss the case.
对方律师不知怎么搞到了
The lawyer on the other side somehow got a copy
-我假文凭的副本  -迈克  那就是胡说
- of my fake diploma. - Mike, that's bullshit.
你的过往和这个案子没有任何关系
Your history has nothing to do with this case.
我知道  但是他让法官向着他那边了
I know that, but he got the judge on his side,
他也会试着对陪审团故技重施
and he's gonna try and do the same thing with the jury,
我的委托人也不太相信我
and my own client barely trusts me.
好吧  你准备怎么做
Okay, what are you gonna do?
我想你能不能为我接手这个案子
I was wondering if you would take over the case for me.
如果你想这么做的话  我很荣幸
If that's what you want, then I would be honored to.
亚历克斯  很高兴你能打电话来
Alex, I'm glad you called.
我们还在做文书工作
We're still working out the paperwork--
如果你们还在做文书工作
If you're still working on the paperwork,
为什么我刚发现你们在挖我的客户
how come I just found out you're trying to poach my client?
-什么  -别跟我打哈哈
- What? - Don't bullshit me.
凯文・鲍尔告诉我皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
Kevin Bauer told me that PSL called
打电话预约见面
to set an appointment,
当然不是告诉我的客户
and it sure as hell wasn't to tell my own client
我要去你的律所当冠名合伙人了
that I'm going to be name partner at your firm.
该死
God damn it.
你是说你和这件事没有关系吗
You're telling me you had nothing to do with this?
我就是这个意思
That's exactly what I'm telling you.
那你最好想点办法
Then get your shit together
这件事成不成都行
and either make this thing happen or not
但我之前为你担过一次风险
'cause I went out on a limb for you once before.
我不会让同样的事情再发生一次
I'm not about to let the same thing happen again.
你安排和辉瑞见面了
Did you set a meeting with Pfizer?
哈维  你不理解
Harvey, you don't understand.
我的理解是你一开始同意
What I understand is you were on board
把亚历克斯拉过来  接着你又去
with bringing Alex over, and then you tried
-偷他的客户  -不是这样的
- to poach his client. - It's not like that.
我知道你想要的是其实是辉瑞
I knew what you really wanted was Pfizer,
-所以我才想办成这件事  -不  路易
- so I tried to make it happen. - No, Louis, what I really
我想要的是把我认识了十五年的
wanted was to bring over my friend who I've known
-朋友带过来  -是吗
- for the last 15 years. - Yeah?
那就不管你的朋友我怎么想了
Well, what about what this friend thinks?
我们已经讨论过这件事了
We already had that discussion,
然后你又背着我做这样的事
and then you went behind my back.
那也许是因为你提议任命你朋友
Maybe because it was stupid of you to offer your friend
-来做合伙人很愚蠢  -你说什么
- name partner in the first place. - Excuse me?
什么样的天才谈判人会一开始
What kind of genius negotiator gives away the house
-就放弃控制权  -路易...
- from the start? - Louis--
别说了  你想要辉瑞
No, you want Pfizer?
你去拿辉瑞
You go get Pfizer.
但是不要随便带进来什么新人
But don't you bring in some Johnny-come-lately
稀释公司的质量
and water down the name of this firm.
你才不在乎稀不稀释公司质量
You don't give a shit about watering down this firm.
你是怕自己被人挤下去
You're scared of watering down your place in it.
我才不怕什么三流律师
I'm not afraid of a third-rate lawyer.
胡说  你不仅害怕  你还嫉妒
Bullshit, you're afraid and you're jealous.
-而且整间公司都知道  -现在没有必要
- And this entire firm knows it. - Now there's no need
嫉妒  因为他不会来了
to be jealous because he's not coming here.
他会来的
Yes, he is.
那你应该去读一下公司章程
Well, then why don't you try reading the by-laws?
因为要任命合伙人
Because in order to make someone name partner,
你需要我投票或者杰西卡投票  如果你以为
you need my vote or Jessica's vote, and if you think
她会为了什么根本不认识的人
she is going to ditch her oldest client to bring in
抛下她最老的客户  那你才是疯了
someone she doesn't even know, you're out of your goddamn mind.
哈维  能给我一分钟吗
Harvey, do you have a minute?
我也就只有这么点时间了
That's about all I have.
好  我想问问能不能
Okay, I was wondering if it would be okay
让我接迈克的无偿服务案
if I took over Mike's pro bono case.
-什么  -出事了
- What? - Something came up.
他问我能不能接
He asked me if I could do it.
-我  我想先征得你的同意  -不行
- I--I wanted to get your permission first. - No.
为什么不行
Why not?
因为和我达成协议的是迈克  不是你
Because I made a deal with Mike, not you.
现在你想告诉我到底怎么回事吗
Now, you wanna tell me what's really going on here?
因为除非迈克昏迷了
Because Mike's not giving away
否则绝不会放弃他的第一个案子
his first case unless he's in a coma.
对方律师说迈克是诈骗犯
The lawyer on the other side outed Mike as a fraud.
-什么意思  -他拿出了迈克的哈佛学位证
- Meaning? - He brought out Mike's Harvard diploma,
让法官对他产生了偏见
and he prejudiced the judge.
所以迈克认为如果他把案子推给你
So Mike thinks if he hands the case over to you,
对方律师就不能用这个武器了
he takes that weapon out of their hands.
-是的  -这下我是坚决不同意了
- Yes. - Well, now it's a definite no.
为什么就成坚决不同意了
Why does that make it a definite no?
因为这是我的决定
Because I said so.
哈维  你能至少和迈克谈谈吗
Harvey, can you at least talk to Mike?
不  我不能
No, I can't.
-为什么  -因为我要赶飞机
- Why not? - Because I got a plane to catch.
你有事找我
You wanted to talk to me?
你从哪看出来的  九条短信还是十六条留言
What gave it away? The nine texts or the 16 messages?
我刚刚在飞机上
I was on a plane.
而我在你以前的办公室里思考
Yeah, well, I'm in your old office wondering why you even
如果你都不让我做简单人员安排
gave it to me if you're not gonna let me make
为什么还要把办公室给我
simple personnel decisions.
迈克  如果你让这个混蛋欺负了你
Mike, if you let this asshole bully you, you're gonna be
那你以后见谁都得让步
backing down for the rest of your life.
我没有在让步  我是在争取时间
I'm not backing down. I am buying time
以避免以后再发生这种事
so that I can stop this bullshit from ever happening again.
你不需要时间  我有办法
You don't need time. I have a way.
停止道歉  开始威胁
Stop apologizing and start intimidating.
标语很好  哈维
Well, that's a hell of a slogan, Harvey,
但这到底是什么意思
but what does it actually mean?
意思是你现在出去  找个记者
It means you go out, you find a reporter,
你说出你的故事
and you take control of the narrative.
成为一个赎罪的英雄
Instead of a lying fraud,
而不是撒谎的骗子
you're a hero fighting for redemption.
我现在没时间改变我的形象
I don't have time to change my image.
听着  如果我输了这个案子
Look, if I lose this case,
唯一写出来的文章会是
the only article that's gonna get written is that I never
我一开始就不该做律师
should have been able to practice law in the first place.
如果你想不出不用瑞秋帮忙
Yeah, well, if you can't figure out a way to win
就能赢的办法  那也许我一开始
without Rachel's help, then maybe I shouldn't have
就不应该让你回来
brought you back in the first place
因为我已经受够了我的每一位员工
because I've had about enough of having every employee
质疑我做的每一个决定
I have question every decision I make.
不是说餐厅见吗
I thought we were gonna meet at the restaurant.
我提前过来了
I got down here early.
曼哈顿没有这样的景色
Manhattan doesn't have views like this.
谢谢你腾出时间来见我  杰西卡
Thanks for making the time to see me, Jessica.
我永远会为你腾时间  哈维
I will always make time to see you, Harvey.
尤其是你都特意飞到这边来
Especially after you've flown all the way out here
-逼我就范了  -路易打电话给你了对吗
- to put the screws to me. - Louis called you, didn't he?
大概在你飞机起飞一小时后
About an hour after your plane took off.
那你已经听了他那个版本的故事了
Then you've already heard his side of the story--
我不需要听你的版本
And I don't need to hear yours.
-杰西卡  -哈维  我明白
- Jessica-- - Harvey, I understand
你想声明所有权  但你要仓促行事
wanting to make a statement, but, you rush into this,
你唯一能说明就是你还没准备好
the only statement you're making is that you're not ready.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
这是我作为经营合伙人的
My first act as managing partner,
第一个决定  你却要来个釜底抽薪
and you're cutting my legs out from under me.
我不是要釜底抽薪
I'm not cutting anything out.
我是想帮你  你不能把合伙人头衔
I'm trying to help you. You can't give out name partner
当万圣节糖果去发
like it's Halloween candy.
这听着不像要帮我  而是把我当孩子
That doesn't sound like help. That sounds like I'm a child--
哈维  如果你这次让步  下次
Harvey, you do this, what's gonna happen
你再想带人过来会怎么样
the next time you wanna bring someone over?
我告诉你会怎么样  你会被迫就范
I'll tell you what happens-- you're going to get rolled
因为你没看清楚这件事
because you haven't thought this through.
你知道我怎么想吗
You know what I think?
我想这跟我做什么决定没关系
I think this has nothing to do with my decision.
是我为更大的客户抛弃你的客户让你生气
You're pissed I'm dumping your client for a better one.
不  哈维  你才会为这种事生气
No, Harvey, that's something you'd be pissed about
因为你从来就没有大局观念
because you've never been able to look at the big picture.
我告诉你我的大局观念
Well, how's this for big picture?
那就是你想要鱼与熊掌兼得
I think you want it both ways.
这话什么意思
And what the hell is that supposed to mean?
意思是你既想待在这边
It means you want to live here
又想把名字留在我律所的墙上  因为
and keep your name on my wall because you're not ready
你还不愿放手我的律所
to let go of my firm.
如果你真这么想
Well, if that's how you really feel,
那就把我的名字拆下来
then take my name off your goddamn wall,
然后爱干什么干什么
and then you can do whatever the hell you want.
你可别以为我忘了我们约好的晚餐
Hey, I hope you don't think I forgot about our dinner.
没有  只是我恐怕得换个时间
Yeah, I don't, but I'm afraid I have to reschedule.
好的  我随时都有空
Sure, any time is good for me.
谢谢你的理解
Thanks for being understanding.
而且我要说  我很期盼
And, for the record, I was really looking forward
我们能进一步加深了解
to getting to know each other better.
我也是
So was I.
但说实话  我很高兴我们换时间
But the truth is I guess I'm glad we're rescheduling.
我不想像上次那样
I didn't want to end up focusing on myself
只关注我自己的事
like I did the last time.
怎么  发生什么事了吗
Why, is something going on?
没什么
It's not a big deal.
哈维  你可以跟我说说
Harvey, you can talk to me about it.
-但你之前说过...  -我知道
- But you said before-- - I know what I said before,
-但这次不同  -怎么不同
- but this is different. - How?
因为接受了我的话  尊重了我的意愿
Because you heard me, and you respected my wishes,
说明我不再只是听你说话的心理医生了
which means instead of me listening to you as your therapist,
我愿意听你说话  作为你的...
you know, I'll be listening to you as your...
不是心理医生的人
Not therapist.
-是啊  -看看
- Yes. - Look at this,
虽然取消见面  我感觉反而更了解你一些了
even when we cancel, I feel like I'm getting to know you better.
我也是
Me too.
那你要告诉我出什么事了吗
So are you gonna tell me what's going on?
其实
You know what?
我们这通电话后
Now that I just talked to you,
我感觉我好像可以自己解决了
I feel like I can work it through myself.
很好
Good.
晚安  哈维
Good night, Harvey.
-忙吗  -你知道我很忙
- You busy? - You know I am, which means
所以如果没有要紧事  你也不会来找我
you wouldn't be here if it wasn't important.
没错  我跟哈维谈过了
You're right. I talked to Harvey.
-你让他回心转意了吗  -没有
- You changed his mind? - No, no.
他说如果我中途退缩  就会退缩一辈子
He told me if I run from this, I'll be running forever.
虽然不想承认  但他说的有点道理
Look, I hate to say it, but he might have a point.
-的确  -那你怎么还来找我
- He does. - So then why are you here?
因为他让我想到  我在那见的第一个
'Cause he got me thinking. The woman I first met over there
女人说  他们不会让哈利和他的妻子这种人
said they couldn't let people like Harry and his wife get away
在申请表上撒谎这种事上得逞
with lying on their application
否则他们生意就没法做了
because they wouldn't have a business anymore.
没错  但是他们没在申请表上撒谎
Right, but they didn't lie on their application.
是  他们没有
No, they didn't.
但如果一家公司会这么想...
But a company that thinks like that...
也许也会想办法逃避索赔
Might have a policy of trying to not pay their claims at all.
正是如此
Exactly.
所以只要我们证明这家公司的真正政策
So if we can prove that that's the company's real policy,
那就赢定了
we got 'em.
但是  不管我们申请多少传票
But, right, Mike, we can get all the subpoenas in the world,
他们也不会乖乖交出证据啊
but they're never going to hand over a smoking gun like that.
他们是不会
No, they won't.
但你认识一个不用传票就能帮我们
But I think you know someone who can get it for us
拿到证据的人
without issuing any subpoena at all.
科伦维尔小姐  还记得我吗
Ms. Cromwell, remember me?
很不幸还记得  失陪了
Yes, unfortunately. If you'll excuse me.
我们有份工作给你
We have a job we'd like to offer you.
-没兴趣  -你都没听是什么工作
- Not interested. - You haven't even heard what it is.
我没必要知道...
I don't need to know what it is--
我不跟信不过的人合作
I don't do business with people I don't trust.
-你是企业间谍  -不再是了...
- You're a corporate spy. - Not anymore--
因为她上次带过来的神秘人
'cause the last mystery man she brought me said word
保证说这件事不会传扬出去
wouldn't get out about our little arrangement.
但还是传出去了  所以现在我是正当猎头
Well, it did, so now I'm trying to make it as a legitimate headhunter,
挣的佣金只有以前的百分之十
which pays about 10% of what I made before,
失陪  我几分钟后我要见一位
so, if you'll excuse me, I'm meeting with
正经客户
an actual client in a few minutes.
科伦维尔小姐  拜托了
Ms. Cromwell, please.
一位年仅39岁的年轻母亲车祸过世
A mother of three was killed in a car accident,
留下了三个孩子
and she was 39 years old.
她的丈夫没钱抚养
Now her husband can't support his children
因为聪明人保险公司企图拒绝赔付
because Acumen Insurance is trying to scam him out of their claim.
你们指望我做什么
What am I supposed to do about that?
他们绝不是第一次这么做
This can't be the first time they've done this.
我们敢肯定纽约没什么大企业
And we're betting that there isn't a major corporation in this city
-是你弄不到消息的  -求你了
- that you don't have access to. - Please.
你可以帮助他们
You can help these people.
我才不想帮别人
I don't give a shit about helping people.
我只想帮自己
I give a shit about helping me,
-所以我要五万美元  -什么
- which is why I want $50,000. - What?
我说了...你们害我损失惨重
I just told you-- you cost me millions.
-如果想要我帮忙  -算了
- So if you want my help-- - Okay, never mind.
迈克  我就知道这样行不通
Mike, I knew this was a bad idea.
-我们可以支付  -迈克
- We'll pay it. - Mike.
瑞秋  如果她真能搞到有用的东西
Rachel, if she can get us something we can use,
这个钱就花的值  钱从和解提议中扣
it's worth it. It'll come out of the settlement offer.
我要预支
Uh-uh, I want it up front.
我们怎么知道你不会拿了钱
And how do we know that you won't take the money and say
-还说你什么也没找到  -你没法知道
- that you couldn't find anything? - You don't,
但你们还杵在这里
but, given the fact that you're still here,
说明你们没有多少选择的余地
it doesn't look like you have much of a choice.
最近怎么样  路易
So how are you, Louis?
想知道我怎么样  那我就好好说说
Wanna know how I'm doing? I'll tell you how I'm doing.
我想把重心放在工作上
I tried focusing on my professional life
而不是个人私事  结果灾难一场
instead of my personal one, and it's been a goddamn disaster.
我想是因为你心里想着塔拉的事
I take it your thoughts of Tara have been getting
-妨碍了你的工作  -什么
- in the way of work. - What?
不  我已经忘了她  故事翻篇了
No, I'm over her-- she's yesterday's news.
听你的话好像不是这么回事
Your words make me think otherwise.
那你好好听听我的话
Well, how about you listen to these words:
哈维要让他一个朋友做冠名合伙人
Harvey's making his friend name partner.
他还说是我在妒忌  我不知道怎么办
He's accused me of being jealous, and I don't know what to do.
那你是在妒忌吗
Are you jealous?
我当然妒忌死了
Of course I'm goddamn jealous!
路易  你有这种感觉很正常
Louis, it's natural for you to feel that way.
你卖力工作才有了今天的地位
You've worked hard to get where you are,
突然冒出一个人对你产生威胁
and a new person threatens your position in the firm.
不是...不是这样的
That's not-- That's just not it.
杰西卡离开的唯一好处
The one silver lining of Jessica leaving
就是我以为哈维终于能够重视我
was that I thought that Harvey would finally turn to me,
不仅作为合伙人  而且作为朋友
not only as his partner, but as his friend.
但这希望破灭了  因为我快被人替代了
That's not happening now because I'm being replaced.
所以你在害怕失去朋友
And you're scared of losing your friend.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
我无法告诉你答案  路易
I can't tell you that, Louis,
但我要告诉你
but I can tell you
是你的所作所为导致塔拉离你而去
it was your behavior that drove Tara away,
如果你继续放任自己感情用事
and, if you keep letting your emotions dictate your behavior,
也不用再担心被他人替代
you won't need to worry about being replaced.
因为你自己就会亲手把哈维推开
You'll drive Harvey away all by yourself.
从来没见过你加班这么晚
I'm not sure I've ever seen you here this late.
新办公室  新作息表
New office, new hours.
我想也是
I guess so.
卡特里娜  你想说什么
Katrina, whatever's on your mind,
直说就好
I recommend you just say it.
你知道  我在律所的目标是高级合伙人
As you know, I'm on track to be a senior partner here.
事实上  这也是我答应回来的主要原因之一
In fact, it's one of the main reasons I agreed to come back.
我知道
I know.
我不是说你不应该提拔唐娜...
I'm not saying Donna doesn't deserve a promotion--
我知道她不比任何人的功劳小
I know what she does as much as anyone.
我只是想说成为合伙人意义重大
I'm just saying making partner means something,
而我担心这个先例会破坏这个意义
and I'm concerned that being one here won't mean what it used to.
你想让我怎么做
What would you have me do?
我不知道  我只是觉得
I don't know. I just thought,
我有这个想法  那其他人可能也会这么想
if I was thinking it, it occurred to me that others might be too,
我觉得应该告诉你
and I thought you should know that.
卡特里娜  成为合伙人的意义将一如既往
Katrina, being a partner here will mean as much as it always has.
我会保证这一点
I'll make sure of it.
我希望你是来告诉我
I hope you came here to tell me
你把事情都搞定了
you got everything straightened out.
我来是想告诉你  我们的约定作废
I came here to tell you that the deal's off the table.
你说什么
What?
冠名合伙人意义重大  我不能
Name partner means something, and I can't just give it away
为了立威随便给人  我最初就不该
to make a statement. I never should've offered it to you
-给你这个提议  -该死  哈维
- in the first place. - God damn it, Harvey.
这是你第二次放我水了
This is the second time you've done this.
抱歉  亚历克斯  但这事没有商量
And I'm sorry, Alex, but this is a take it or leave it offer.
你可以考虑到明天
You can let me know in the morning.
我接受
I'll take it.
我其实不可能在一年内成为冠名合伙人
I wasn't really gonna make name partner in a year.
也许永远成为不了
Maybe not ever.
我知道
I know.
你怎么知道
How?
因为如果他们真能一年内给你
Because if they were really gonna do it in a year,
在我离开你办公室那一刻
you would've leveraged them to move it up
你就会利用我的条件要他们现在就给
the second I left your office.
那你之前为什么没揭穿我
So why didn't you call me on that before?
我不知道
I don't know.
或许是因为我觉得亏欠你
Maybe it's because I felt like I owe you,
也或许是因为我想向外界证明
or maybe because I wanted to prove to the world
我不是杰西卡
that I'm not Jessica.
又或许是因为  我就是单纯想跟你共事
Or maybe it's because I wanted to work together.
我们周一见  哈维
I'll see you Monday, Harvey.
周一见
See you Monday.
我来付吧
I'll get that.
省省吧  罗斯先生
Keep your money, Mr. Ross.
你赚大钱的日子快到头了
You're gonna need it.
我觉得等你看了这个
I think, after you see this,
恐怕一分钱都要掰成两半花了
you're gonna wanna save every nickel you have.
谢谢
Thanks.
如果错了请更正我  但我想这是
Now, correct me if I'm wrong, but I believe that's a memo
欧酷曼公司高管及其销售人员的备忘录
between Acumen senior management and their sales force
所列政策显示他们会不顾一切
outlining their policy of doing whatever it takes
避免支付保险金
to avoid paying claims.
这可以从很多角度来解读
Well, this thing can be interpreted a dozen different ways.
证明不了什么
It doesn't prove a thing.
但它证明此事不再仅仅关乎我的委托人
But it proves that we're not just talking about my client anymore.
你需要担心的是集体诉讼了
You're looking at a class action.
唯一能比冒牌律师
And if there's one thing that a jury hates
更招陪审团讨厌的  就是一家
more than a fake lawyer, it's an insurance company
剥削鳏夫和幼小的保险公司
that rips off widowers and children.
-你想要什么  -五千万
- What do you want? - 50 million.
同时保险公司认罪
With an admission of guilt.
不行  他们不可能认罪
No way, they won't go for admission.
好吧  那你还有一条路可选
Okay, then here's what you're gonna do instead.
有记者会联系你
A reporter's gonna call you.
然后你告诉他  你本以为
And when he does, you're gonna tell him the story of
可以羞辱一位冒牌律师
how you thought you were gonna wipe the floor
但结果是你开始祈祷
with this fraudulent attorney, but instead you ended up praying
永远不在庭上再遇到他
that you never go up against him again.
你早知道他们不会认罪
You knew they wouldn't go for admission.
给我挖坑让我往里跳
You set me up.
既然你这么说  我就不否认了
Well, now that you mention it,I did.
一口价  没商量
And that's take it or leave it.
那我接受吧
Then I guess I'll take it.
我就不提你为了给自己脸上贴金
And leave out the part where you traded admission of guilt
放弃公司认罪的事了
in exchange for self-promotion.
你没资格跟我说这种话
Don't you dare say that to me.
我这么做不是为了自己
I'm not doing this for myself.
而是为了让你这样的混蛋
I'm doing it so that pieces of shit like you
永远别再想利用我的黑历史攻击我的委托人
never try to use my history against my clients again.
路易  在你开口前...
Louis, before you say anything...
哈维  在你开口前
Harvey, before you say anything,
我想先说声对不起
I just wanna say I'm sorry.
你是对的
You were right.
我是嫉妒亚历克斯来  但不是因为
I was jealous of Alex coming over here, but not because
-我怕来自律师的竞争  -我没听懂
- I'm afraid of another lawyer. - I don't understand.
听着  哈维  我知道你喜欢拿我开心
See, Harvey, I know you like to make fun of me,
我也知道也许我对你的意义并没有
and I know I might not mean as much to you
你对我的意义重大  但你是我朋友
as you mean to me, but you're my friend,
而且我又没几个朋友  所以这份友谊
and, because I don't have many, that friendship
对我来说很重要
is important to me.
你不用担心这一点  路易
You don't have to worry about that, Louis.
但我不希望我的行为导致我们产生隔阂
But I don't want my behavior to drive a wedge between us,
所以我接受亚历克斯成为冠名合伙人
which means I accept Alex as name partner.
-关于这点  路易...  -这就像
- About that, Louis... - I mean, it's just gonna
勒布朗・詹姆斯加入迈阿密热队的时候
have to be like when LeBron James joined the Miami Heat
他和韦德是怎样跟克里斯・波什处理关系的
when he and D-Wade worked it out with Chris Bosh.
我以为你对体育一窍不通
I thought you didn't know anything about sports.
我为了想个合适的类比熬了一整晚
I stayed up all night trying to come up with the right analogy.
而且如果我没记错  他们后来
And, if I'm not mistaken, they went on to
在超级杯取得了连胜
win back-to-back Super Bowls.
也没错
That they did.
路易  不管怎样  亚历克斯还是要来
Louis, for what it's worth, Alex is still coming,
-但他不会成为冠名合伙人  -真的吗
- but not as name partner. - Really?
是的  你说得对
Yeah, you were right.
不该这样稀释公司的质量
We can't water down the firm like that.
你以前从不敲门的
You've never knocked before.
你的办公室以前也没有门
And you've never had a door before.
我知道  有门是件好事  因为...
I know, and it's a good thing I do because--
你不能当合伙人  唐娜
You can't be a partner, Donna.
什么
What?
你不能这样
You can't do that.
我不得不这样  我犯了个错误
I have to. I made a mistake.
扯淡  我付了你五十万
Bullshit, I-- I paid you $500,000.
你还没签合伙协议  所以
You haven't signed the partnership agreement yet,
我可以把钱退给你  然后...
so I can refund your money, and--
我不要退款  我要你说到做到
I don't want a refund. I want what we agreed to.
我做不到
I can't do that.
你不是律师出身  而律所合伙人...
You are not a lawyer, and being partner at a law firm--
是有意义的  在公司内外分量都不轻
it means something, inside the firm and out,
所以我重新起草了一份聘任合同
which is why I wrote up a new release for you.
你写的是"人事部部长"
This says "Director of Personnel."
大家都知道你对于人事管理很有一套
Everybody knows you're great with people,
对外这样讲  但就你我而言...
so it'll play out there, but, between you and me--
不  哈维  我要当合伙人不是为了
No, Harvey, I didn't ask for partner just so I could
继续无名无份的做女超人拯救一切
keep being a superwoman behind closed doors,
而在外人眼里只是个名头好的办公室主任
but, to the rest of the world, be a glorified office manager.
合伙人绝对不可能  唐娜
Partner is off the table, Donna.
那留着我的买进股资  我要当首席运营官
Then keep my buy-in and make me COO.
这我也做不到  这和合伙人是一回事
I can't do that-- that's the same as a partner.
不是  世达・赞恩  布莱顿・古尔德
No, it isn't. Skadden and Zane
都有首席运营官  而且都不是律师出身
and Bratton Gould all have COOs, and none of them are lawyers.
你怎么会知道这些
How do you know that?
因为我一开始就知道
'Cause I never thought you'd make me partner
你不会让我当合伙人
in the first place.
好吧  成交
Okay, it's a deal.
而且我要留着我的投票权
And I keep my vote.
-唐娜...  -私底下
- Donna-- - Within these walls,
仍然要有我的一席之地  一口价
I have a seat at the table. Take it or leave it.
我接受
I'll take it.
谢谢你  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
你会是个很棒的首席运营官
You're gonna make a hell of a COO.
怎么样  顺利吗
And? How'd it go?
精彩极了
Out of the park.
我们想要的都拿到了
Got everything we wanted.
我们今晚出去庆祝一下怎么样
What do you say we go out and celebrate tonight?
我们要庆祝  但是不能出门了
Well, we're celebrating, but we're not going out.
什么意思
What do you mean?
《时代周刊》有个记者五分钟后就到
A reporter from "The Times" Is gonna be here in five minutes.
-好吧  -我们要接受个采访
- Okay. - We are doing an interview.
欺诈律师的救赎之路
The redemption of a fraudulent lawyer.
这是自你进入律师协会以来
Well, that is the best news I've heard since finding out
-最好的消息  -谢谢
- you got into the bar. - Thank you.
但我觉得你应该自己接受采访
But I think you should do it without me.
瑞秋  没有你  我根本做不到这一切
Rachel, I--I couldn't have done any of this without you.
或许如此  但这是你自己的故事
And that may be true, but this is your story,
应该由你亲自讲述
and you should be the one to tell it.
去吧  我在家等你
Go--I'll see you at home.
-迈克  -你好
- Mike? - Yeah.
-我是大卫・格鲁因  -很高兴认识你
- David Gruen. - Good to meet you.
你想在哪里做采访
Where do you want to do this?
我觉得你的新办公室很合适
I was thinking maybe your new office.
不错  那里可以当最后一站
Uh, yeah, we could end up there.
但我觉得或许应该从我起步的地方开始
But I was thinking maybe we'd start out where I started out.
-那是哪里  -大办公室
- Where's that? - In the bullpen.
又怎么了  哈维
What is it now, Harvey?
想让门房负责破产事务吗
You want to put the janitor in charge of bankruptcy?
还是让楼下的保安做诉讼带头人
Or the guard downstairs could be head of litigation.
-发泄完了吗  -那要看你接下来说什么
- Are you finished? - Depends on what you say next.
很抱歉我那么说你
I'm sorry I said those things about you,
我想跟你说  我心里并不那么想
and I want you to know I didn't mean any of them.
我也很抱歉  哈维
I'm sorry too, Harvey.
杰西卡  你不用道歉的
Jessica, you don't need to apologize.
不  我用
Yes, I do.
你只是在拆我的雕像
You were just tearing the statue down.
就像很多年前你看着我做的一样的事
Just like you saw me do all those years ago,
而我不开心
and I didn't like it
只是因为这次是我的雕像
because the statue was me.
如果你不介意
Well, if it's the same to you,
我希望留下你的雕像
I'd like the statue to stay.
我觉得可以
Sounds good to me.
-还有件事  -一向如此
- There's one more thing. - There always is.
亚历克斯还是会进律所  不当冠名合伙人
I'm still bringing Alex over, only not as a name partner,
但辉瑞制药仍坚持让我们放弃吉姆・雷诺兹
but Pfizer's still insisting we drop Jim Reynolds.
你想知道我能不能接受
And you want to know if I'm okay with it?
不  我肯定要放弃他
No, I'm letting him go.
只是在告诉他之前先打电话告诉你
I'm just calling you to tell you before I tell him,
做我一开始就该做的事
like I should've done in the first place.
当我说你还没准备好时  我错了  哈维
I was wrong when I said you weren't ready, Harvey.
不  当时没错
No, you weren't,
错的是这句
but you are now.
晚安  高手
Good night, Closer.
晚安  杰西卡
Good night, Jessica.
还有  不许把脚搭在我桌子上
And take your feet off my desk.
没门
Not a chance.